# Nikos Baxevanis

## Software Developer/Architect, Sr

Forward-thinking developer/architect problem-solves and collaborates with clients and company personnel. 15+ years of experience across a broad range of technologies and sectors, with a strong interest in crafting high quality solutions, using functional programming, object-oriented design, and test-driven development.

## **Work History**

#### 2021-07 -Current

### Product Developer, Sr

Epicor, Austin, Remote

- Establishing Epicor CPQ (formerly KBMax)
  backend migration from Azure Service Fabric to
  Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS).
- Increasing Azure SQL Server DB schema updates throughput to thousands of DBs concurrently.
- Managing new Epicor CPQ developer hires with their onboarding process, knowledge transfer, setup Git/Bitbucket group policies.

#### 2014-06 -2021-06

## Core Developer

KBMax, San Francisco, Remote

- Wrote, modified and maintained software entirely on Microsoft Azure.
- Performed unit testing, system testing and integration testing.
- As an early stage employee, participated heavily in design development meetings with the company founders.
- Set up scripts, test case and automation protocols with Azure DevOps/Pipelines.
- Diagnosed and corrected errors within code to allow for integration with other platforms, including MuleSoft and Salesforce.
- Optimized Azure SQL schema update performance using Azure Queues and Azure Workers.
- Performed troubleshooting and diagnostics on Azure Monitor/Application Insights to uncover root malfunctions.
- Reviewed code on **Git** and debugged errors to improve performance.
- Acquired by Epicor on May 2021.

#### Contact

#### **Address**

Zlín

#### Phone

+420 774 582 384

#### E-mail

cv@nikosbaxevanis.com

#### **Twitter**

nikosbaxevanis

#### **Skills**

C#, F#, ASP.NET, Azure

Haskell, Property testing

Test-Driven Development

SOLID, OOD, Architecture

REST API, Web Services

Microservices, Monoliths

Docker, Git, Visual Studio

Sublime Text, Vim, Bash

Smart Contracts, Ethereum

Stacks, Fuzz testing, RPC

WPF, WCF, XAML, MEF

Dependency Injection, ORM

Dapper, Entity Framework

Redis, Elasticsearch, SQL Server

SQL Azure, Azure DevOps

Azure Pipelines, Azure Queues

# 2013-01 - Core Developer 2020-06

Cryptean, Grand Cayman, Remote

- Designed and implemented smart contract fuzzing using Haskell QuickCheck, F# Hedgehog, and TypeScript fast-check.
- Co-founded Hedgehog, Haskell and F# testing tool that automatically generates test cases, detecting unexpected bugs.
- Hedgehog has been established in the Ethereum community (Echidna, IOHK, and others).
- Implemented automated trading scripts for centralized exchanges in Node.js (CCXT).
- Maintained Bitcoin node .NET client, BitcoinLib.

### 2009-01 -2012-05

#### **Co-founder and CTO**

BetKernel, Valletta, Remote

- Co-founded BetKernel, ultimate new generation auto-betting platform with real-time analysis on experts' advices, statistics, market trends and last-minute news.
- BetKernel was acquired on May 2012.

#### 2010-01 -2011-01

## **Software Development Lead Architect**

European Union Minettas Insurance, Athens

 Architected and implemented rewrite of existing IBM AS/400 infrastructure in Microsoft .NET Framework.

### 2005-06 -2009-01

## **Software Development Lead**

Topologic, Athens

- Implemented highly available fleet tracking systems in .NET
- Autodesk AutoCAD Map/Civil 3D integrations using Java Topology Suite via IKVM.NET.

## **Education**

# 2002-09 - Bachelor of Science: Biomedical Engineering

Technological Educational Institute - Athens

- Developed a highly scalable, real-time, healthcare web application as graduation project.
- Presented in the Department of Medical Instruments of Technology at Medic Expo 2009.